
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>sketchtips.info</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info</link>
<description>Clever tips for your favourite design app.</description>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<atom:link href="http://www.sketchtips.info/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />


<item>
<title>How to make a layout-grid</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=41</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>L</kbd></p>

<p>Note: The terms of &ldquo;grid&rdquo; and &ldquo;layout&rdquo; are used a bit ambigious in Sketch. A grid, which you typically use on a website or app to align content, is actually called &ldquo;layout&rdquo;, while a &ldquo;grid&rdquo; is just a raster of evenly spaced vertical and horizontal lines for easier alignment. However, in this article I&rsquo;d like to talk about Sketch&rsquo;s &ldquo;layout&rdquo; option which I call &ldquo;grid&rdquo; in the following to use the proper term.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jul-02-2014-1.png" width="726" height="447" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the 'layout' dialog" class="resrc" data-resrc-dpi="2"/></figure>

<p>Since grids are one of the most essential starting points for a design, they are an inherent part of Sketch. To toggle the grid press <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>g</kbd> or select &ldquo;View > Show/Hide layout&rdquo; in either the menubar or toolbar. Now a default grid is shown which you can change with &ldquo;View > Layout Settings...&rdquo;. The following dialog has numerous options to adjust. On the top you can define the &ldquo;Width&rdquo; of the grid and the &ldquo;Number of Columns&rdquo;. Unfortunately the width can only be set in pixels &ndash; if you need a percentage you have to do the math by yourself. Right beneath is a handy &ldquo;Center&rdquo; button and the option &ldquo;Gutter on outside&rdquo;, which distributes half of the set &ldquo;Gutter width&rdquo; on the left and right outside of the grid. If you have set &ldquo;20px&rdquo; then 10px are added to the left side of the grid and 10px on the right side. If switched off the grid is exactly as wide as set at the &ldquo;Width&rdquo;.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jul-02-2014-2.png" width="726" height="377" alt="Screenshot of Sketch with the description of the different parts of a grid" class="resrc" data-resrc-dpi="2"/></figure>

<p>Next you find the aforementioned field for &ldquo;Gutter Width&rdquo;, which determines how wide the spaces in between the columns are and &ldquo;Column Width&rdquo;, which determines the width of columns set at &ldquo;Number of Columns&rdquo; above. The &ldquo;Guter Width&rdquo; is automatically adjusted based on the &ldquo;Total width&rdquo;, &ldquo;Number of Columns&rdquo; and &ldquo;Column Width&rdquo;, but naturally you can also adjust it which in turn affects the &ldquo;Column Width&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Apart from a grid based on columns it is also possible to make a &ldquo;row&rdquo; grid or combine the both. However a row grid is not as flexible as a column grid. The &rdquo;Gutter Height&rdquo; directly affects the &ldquo;Row height&rdquo;, which is just a multiple of it. So the higher the latter, the bigger the rows get. To show every subdivision of the rows select &ldquo;Draw all horizontal lines&rdquo;. Unfortunateley the most essential &ldquo;row&rdquo; grid, a baseline grid, can&rsquo;t be achieved this way.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Arrows and other border options</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=40</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<figure class="tip-image-right"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jun-25-2014-1.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="225" height="190" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the advanced options for borders" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Some of the options in Sketch are rather hidden. Amongst them are the advanced settings for borders, which can be found if you click on the little gear icon at the border options in the Insector panel. They allow you to:</p>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Set the ends of lines</strong>: They can either be angular and end right at the end of the line, jut out by the half width of the thickness and be rounded or angular (from left to right): <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jun-25-2014-2.png" width="84" height="31" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the end options for lines" class="resrc"/></li>
	<li><strong>Set the joins of lines</strong>: This determines how the corners look where two border lines meet. They can be angular, round or slightly bevelled (from left to right): <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jun-25-2014-3.png" width="84" height="31" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the join options for lines" class="resrc"/></li>
	<li><strong>Make arrows</strong>: Moreover the start and end points of lines can be equipped with three types of arrows. Unfortunateley they only work correctly for borders of 1 or 2 pixels because they are not sized according to their thickness. </li>
	<li><strong>Create dashed/dotted lines</strong>: You can set certain patterns, which determine how long the line and the following gap is. A dotted line for example is represented by the values &ldquo;1-1-1-1&rdquo;, a dashed lines is &ldquo;2-1-2-1&rdquo;. The bigger the "dash" values are, the longer the line segments, the bigger the "gap" values are, the bigger the spaces between the lines. </li>
</ul>

<p>In Sketch 2 these options can be revealed if you click on the little down-pointing arrow at the border options.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Make 9-Slice Image</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=39</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Layer &gt; Convert to 9-Slice Image (Sketch 2: Edit &gt; Convert to 9-Slice Image)</strong></p>

<p>With this option you can divide an image into nine sections, which act differently when you resize it:</p>

<ol>
	<li>The corners get moved.</li>
	<li>The side areas get stretched.</li>
	<li>The part in the middle only gets scaled.</li>
</ol>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jun-11-2014.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="726" height="430" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which descries the different sections of a 9-slice image" class="resrc"/><figcaption class="tip-image-text">Browser frame by <a href="http://medialoot.com/item/browser-mock-up-frames/">Medialoot</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>To apply it just select the bitmap, choose &ldquo;Layer &gt; Convert to 9-Slice Image&rdquo; (Sketch 2: &ldquo;Edit &gt; Convert to 9-Slice Image&rdquo;), drag the four handles to the desired location and confirm the operation with <kbd>enter</kbd>. Whenever you resize the image now the outer parts always keep their original appearance. Like in the screenshot you can use this function for example to make a frame of an app, which never gets distorted when you resize it.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Stroke width</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=38</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Layer &gt; Paths &gt; Stroke Width (Sketch 2: Edit &gt; Paths &gt; Stroke Width)</strong></p>

<p>Although Sketch is quite unflexible regarding irregular strokes there is still an option for this type of modification. After you have created a vector or path make sure that it has a border applied and select the above menu command, which allows you to set various width points. Just click on any position of the border and drag it outwards to set the width of the stroke at this point. Repeat this step until you have the desired result. Please note that the start and end point of the vector can also be modified. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jun-04-2014.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="726" height="251" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows a vector with different width points" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Unfortunately this tool is somewhat unflexible and can sometimes produce unexpected results. Hence it&rsquo;s better to select and delete existing points with <kbd>del</kbd> or <kbd>backspace</kbd> if you are not satisfied. After you are vaguely happy with the width points select &ldquo;Layer > Paths > Vectorize Stroke&rdquo; (Sketch 2: &ldquo;Edit > Paths > Vectorize Stroke&rdquo;) from the menubar, which lets you alter each individual point. Of course the stroke width can also be altered for shapes, but the best results are produced for straight vectors or paths.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Move shape while creating</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=37</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>space</kbd></p>

<figure class="tip-image-right"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-28-2014.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="216" height="216" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the creation of a rectangle plus the text '+ space'" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>Sometimes when you create a shape it can happen that you just don't hit the right spot and it is a bit off. While it&rsquo;s no big effort to move the layer around afterwards, there&rsquo;s an even easier and faster way to correct the misplacement. Just hold <kbd>space</kbd> while creating the shape (don&rsquo;t release the mouse button yet!) and you are able to move it around at will. Release the space key and the layer can be resized again.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Shared styles</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=36</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Compared to Sketch 2 the linking of styles has been slightly optimized in Sketch 3 (<a href="http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=20">read my original tip</a>). This way you can share the fills, borders, shadows, gaussian blur and refelection between multiple elements. Like before it&rsquo;s possible to link the styles of layers on one side and also the styles of text on the other side. However the process is quite similar.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-21-2014-1.jpg" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="726" height="213" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two shapes that share the same style" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>First you have to create the layer or text which should serve as the model for other potential content. Do this as you would normally add content to the canvas. Please note that styles can be shared across different shapes (rectangle to circle, triangle to vector etc.) After that select the layer/text whose styling you want to make available and click on the dropdown in the Inspector which says &ldquo;No Shared Style&rdquo; for shapes or &ldquo;No Text Style&rdquo; for text. Select &ldquo;Create New Shared Style&rdquo; for the former or &ldquo;Create New Text Style&rdquo; for the latter and you&rsquo;re done. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-21-2014-2.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="726" height="118" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two text layers that share the same style" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>Whenever you select another shape or text now, you can choose and apply the newly created style in this dropdown. All the other linked elements get updated immediately after that. To see a list of all the available styles click on &ldquo;Manage Shared Styles&rdquo; in the dropdown. To go even further you can also make symbols, which not only share the styling but also other characteristics like the size or transformations; they can even consist of multiple layers. Read more about symbols in one of my future tips.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Resize layers with the keyboard</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=35</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcuts:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + arrow keys</p>

<figure class="tip-image-right"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-14-2014-1.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="262" height="239" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows a rectangle with the shortscuts to resize it" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>Sometimes pixel-precision is a must if you edit shapes; Sketch makes it very easy to apply this accuary. First you need to select the layer you want to edit. To change its size with the keyboard now hold down <kbd>cmd</kbd>. After that the <kbd>left</kbd> arrow key can be used to shrink its width and the <kbd>right</kbd> arrow key to enlarge it.</p>

<p>The same can be done for the height with the <kbd>up</kbd> and <kbd>down</kbd> arrow keys - the former makes the shape lower, the latter makes it higher. If you attempt to change a layer this way and it resizes proportionally then lock the icon <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-14-2014-2.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="33" height="16" alt="Icon of 'proportional lock'" class="tip-image-inline"> between the width and height input fields in the Inspector is probably selected.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Advanced image editing</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=34</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<figure class="tip-image-left"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-09-2014-5.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="221" height="268" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the image manipulation options" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>Another area where Sketch 3 catched up much compared to its predecessor is image editing (read my <a href="http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=22">initial tip</a>). While the possibilities are still far away from Photoshop, you may not need the former anymore if you want to make some corrections to your image or select certain areas.</p>

<p>To start editing an image you still need to doube-click on it. The most obvious addition is the Magic Wand. It allows you to select similar colored areas. If you just click everything that is within a certain range (which sadly can&rsquo;t be finetuned) gets selected. By clicking and dragging you can progressively enlarge the selected area. Apart from the Magic Wand you can still select rectangular areas. After a selection is made there are four manipulation options to choose from:</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Invert selection</strong> <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-09-2014-1.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="25" height="25" alt="Icon of 'Invert selection'" class="tip-image-inline">: Like the name suggests, everything that is currently selected gets deselected and vice versa. </li>
	<li><strong>Crop</strong> <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-09-2014-2.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="25" height="25" alt="Icon of 'Crop'" class="tip-image-inline">: Everything outside the selection is deleted. If you press <kbd>backspace</kbd> or <kbd>del</kbd> the selection itself is deleted.</li>
	<li><strong>Fill selection</strong> <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-09-2014-3.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="25" height="25" alt="Icon of 'Fill selection'" class="tip-image-inline">: Fill the selection with a solid color. </li>
	<li><strong>Vectorize selection</strong> <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-may-09-2014-4.png" data-resrc-dpi="2" width="25" height="25" alt="Icon of 'Vectorize selection'" class="tip-image-inline">: Possibily the most interesting option. Especially in combination with the Magic Wand it allows you to select certain areas of the image and make a vector shape out of it for further usage. The original image remains untouched with this manipulation.</li>
</ul>

<p>Please beware that every of this manipulations except the last are permanent and alter the actual image, thus they can&rsquo;t be reserved at a later time. In addition to these manipulations you are also able to copy and paste parts of the image with <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>C</kbd> and <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>P</kbd>. To end the image editing click outside the image or press enter or esc.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>View options</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=33</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<figure class="tip-image-right"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-30-2014.png" width="238" height="339" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows a layer and the rulers, grid and some layer guides turned on" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>There are several viewing options and aids in Sketch, which can easily be hidden/shown with shortcuts.</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Show/hide rulers</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>R</kbd>. The main purpose of rulers is to give you a sense of the dimensions of your canvas and layers and to add layer guides.</li>
	<li><strong>Show/hide layer guides</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>L</kbd>. To add a layer guide double-click on the desired position on the ruler. You can learn more about them in my <a href="http://localhost/sketchtips/?tip=8">tip about layer guides</a>.
	<li><strong>Hide/show grid and layout</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>G</kbd>. These two terms can be a bit confusing in Sketch. What you typically understand as a grid in web-design - columns and gutters to align content - is called &ldquo;layout&rdquo; in Sketch. A grid in Sketch on the other side is just a raster of intersecting lines with consistant spacing like shown in the screenshot.</li>
	<li><strong>Hide/show pixels</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>P</kbd>. While Sketch is based on vectors, this option lets you view your layers how they look when they get rastered. Read more about that in <a href="http://localhost/sketchtips/?tip=4">my related tip</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Show/hide pixel grid</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>X</kbd>. As soon as you &ldquo;show pixels&rdquo; in Sketch, a raster is shown when you zoom in to more than 400 %. This shortcut lets you toogle this grid.</li>
	<li><strong>Show/hide selection handles</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>H</kbd>. If you click on a layer in Sketch, tiny grey boxes are shown around it. They let you resize the layer or rotate it if you hold <kbd>cmd</kbd>.</li>
</ul>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Exporting</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=32</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>shift</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>E</kbd></p>

<p>One of the features that changed (and improved) a lot in Sketch 3 is exporting. Earlier it was an entirely separate workflow and always felt a bit clunky. Not only did you have to add slices for every layer you wanted to export, but also needed to adjust this slice if you moved around the layer.</p>

<p>In Sketch 3 there are different approaches to exporting. The easiest way is to select a layer, click on &ldquo;Make Exportable&rdquo; in the bottom right corner of the Inspector and choose the format. Now every time you click on &ldquo;Export&rdquo; <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-24-2014-1.png" width="41" height="41" alt="The Export icon" class="tip-image-inline"> in the toolbar (or press <kbd>shift</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>E</kbd>) all the tagged layers are presented in a handy dialog. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-24-2014-2.jpg" width="726" height="430" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows three layers, which are prepared for beeing exported as well as the Export dialog" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Additionally all the layers that you selected for exporting are presented with an indicator (a little knife <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-24-2014-3.png" width="25" height="23" alt="Indication of a masked layer" class="tip-image-inline">) in the Layers List.</p>

<figure class="tip-image-right"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-24-2014-4.jpg" width="231" height="354" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the options to export a slice" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>However the slices from Sketch 2 are not gone yet, but they are more powerful this time. Firstly they are displayed in the Layers List now so that you can keep track. You also see them permanently in the canvas as dashed lines. To insert a slice press <kbd>S</kbd> and draw a rectangle of the content you want to export. When you click on this rectangle you not only see the clipping in the Inspector but are also presented with various options there. </p>

<p>The process of exporting a whole artboard is very similar, since they are treated like huge slices when you click on them in the Layers List.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Sketch 3 is here</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=31</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>As you may have noticed a couple of days ago <a href="http://bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch 3</a> has been released. The biggest change is probably the inclusion of Symbols which let you finally add reusable elements. Another huge improvement is the revision of exporting which is now an integral part of the app and not a separate dialog anymore. But these are not the only changes, Sketch 3 has been totally overhauled with countless little change, not only to the appearance but also the workflow.</p>

<p>To keep pace I also slightly changed sketchtips and added an indicator to each tip which shows if it applies to Sketch 2, Sketch 3 or both. Additionally I revised each tip to reflect the changes which may have occured from Sketch 2 to Sketch 3. Therefore I was not able to produce a tip this week.</p>

<p>However from now on I will solely focus on Sketch 3 and all screenshots, features and tips will be taken straight from this release. While its predecessor is still a great product and can undoubtedly be used to produce wonderful designs, you definitely should give Sketch 3 a try and experience all of its new features and optimizations. It's definitely worth it.</p> 
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Maximize available space</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=30</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcuts:</em> <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>1</kbd>, <kbd>2</kbd> or <kbd>3</kbd></p>

<p>Especially at smaller screens &ndash; think MacBook Air &ndash; the workspace of Sketch can get crowded pretty fast with the Layers List on the left and the Inspector on the right. To maximize the available space of the canvas you can hide both. For the Layers List press <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>1</kbd>, the Inspector can be hidden with <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>2</kbd>. There&rsquo;s also the option to remove both at the same time with <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>3</kbd>.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-09-2014.png" width="726" height="382" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows 3 of the above shortcuts" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>To get even more screen estate you can also hide the Toolbar with <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>T</kbd>. Lastly, as in many Mac apps, there&rsquo;s the possibility to go into Full Screen mode with <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>F</kbd>.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Dublicate and repeat</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=29</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>A neat trick I have discovered recently in Sketch is the ability to quickly dublicate and repeat layers by the same distance. Actually it&rsquo;s quite easy: Select the layer you want to distribute, press and hold <kbd>alt</kbd> and drag it to the new position. The important thing here is where you move the layer, since all copies will be placed at exactly the same offset. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-apr-02-2014.png" width="726" height="580" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows different layers that are distributed evenly" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>After that press <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>D</kbd> as aften as you want the layer to be dublicated. It&rsquo;s as easy as that. Another way to distribute layers is the <a href="http://sketchtips.info/?tip=16">&ldquo;Grid Tool&rdquo;</a>, which I have already described at sketchtips.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Quickly change opacity</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=28</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Although Sketch and Photoshop couldn&rsquo;t be more different, they have a few things in common &ndash; presumably on purpose. One of these similiarities is the ability to change the opacity of a layer with the numeric keys. The range goes from <kbd>1</kbd> (10 %) to <kbd>0</kbd> (100 %) and all the values in beween.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-26-2014-1.png" width="726" height="400" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which three different opacity levels (10 %, 50 %, 100 %)" class="resrc"></figure>

<p>Unlike in Photoshop however it&rsquo;s not possible to set values below 10 % hereby. For this task you still need to use the slider in the Inspector on the right side: <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-26-2014-2.png" width="194" height="36" alt="Opcity slider" class="tip-image-inline"></p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Masking</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=27</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>M</kbd></p>

<p>One of the essential abilities of any graphical application is masking. Although Sketch is mainly based on vectors and not designed for image editing, it still has some basic functionality here - enough to embellish your mock-ups. To mask an image just insert it into Sketch (the simplest way is to drag it in from the Finder) and draw any shape or vector on the canvas, which will act as the mask. Then move this shape beyond the image (by dragging it in the Layers List or pressing <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>down</kbd>), right click on it in the Layers List and select &ldquo;Use as mask&rdquo; or press <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>M</kbd>. If everything went right the shape should function as a mask now.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-19-2014-1.jpg" width="726" height="506" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows multiple masked images" class="resrc"><figcaption class="tip-image-text">Images by <a href="http://dribbble.com/AndersJilden">Anders Jildén</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/davideragusa">Davide Ragusa</a> and <a href="http://dribbble.com/wojtas">Wojtek Witkowski</a> and  on <a href="http://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>To mask multiple images on the canvas just enclose each shape and image into a separate group (select both and press <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>G</kbd>). A little dot on the left of the layer in the Layers List <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-19-2014-2.png" width="89" height="27" alt="Indication of a masked layer" class="tip-image-inline"> indicates that it is masked by another layer. If you don&rsquo;t want to use a layer as a mask anymore right click on it in the Layers List and uncheck &ldquo;Use As Mask&rdquo;. Of course masking is not limited to images, any shape can also mask another shape - even text. But in this case you have to convert it to outlines first (right click &gt; &ldquo;Convert to Outlines&rdquo;).</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Quick exporting</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=26</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>While the Export option in Sketch is pretty straightforward and easy to use there is an even simpler way to save your files. All you have to do is to click on &ldquo;Export&rdquo; icon <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-12-2014-2.jpg" width="39" height="39" alt="Icon of the 'Export' option" class="tip-image-inline"> in the toolbar (top right corner) and draw a selection around the part of the artboard you want to export. Then drag the little thumbnail of your selection to the desktop or another location like the Finder and it gets immediatley saved as a PNG image. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-12-2014.jpg" width="726" height="458" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the Export option" class="resrc"><figcaption class="tip-image-text">Game Center Icon by <a href="http://codepen.io/rss/pen/vclLe">Riza Selçuk Saydam</a> on <a href="http://sketchmine.co/">sketchmine.co</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>In Sketch 3 it&rsquo;s even easier: Just drag the layer from the Layer List out of Sketch.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Click-through when selecting layers</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=25</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>The more layers and layer groups you have in your document, the harder it gets to select individual layers. The default way to access layers within a group is to double-click on it, which can get pretty tedious for multiple nested groups. To ease this process there are several possibilities in Sketch:</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-mar-05-2014.jpg" width="726" height="388" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the Layers List with multiple layers" class="resrc"><figcaption class="tip-image-text">Jolly Icons by <a href="http://jollyicons.com/">Olly Holovchenko</a> on <a href="http://iconmelon.com/">iconmelon.com</a></figcaption></figure>

<ol>
	<li>In Sketch 2, when a layer group is selected you can check &ldquo;Click-through when selecting&ldquo; in the Inspector (right panel, top area). In Sketch 3 this option is not available anymore. Now it&rsquo;s possible to select nested layers, but you still need to check this option for every nested group within a group. Turn it off by unchecking the checkbox or with a right click on the layer group in the Layers List (left panel) and selecting &ldquo;Click-through&rdquo; (Sketch 3: &ldquo;Toggle Click-through&rdquo;).</li>
	<li>To permanently enable this option you can select &ldquo;Enable Click-through for New Groups&rdquo; in the &ldquo;Layers&rdquo; tab of the Preferences (Sketch > Preferences... or <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>,</kbd>). Please note that this only applies to newly created layer groups. </li>
	<li>The easiest way is to press the <kbd>cmd</kbd> key when pointing at a layer. This enables you to select layers within groups no matter how deeply nested they are.</li>
</ol><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Layer list options</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=24</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<figure class="tip-image-right"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-26-2014-1.jpg" width="214" height="269" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the layer list, amongst them is a hidden, a locked and a selected layer" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Like in every application, the true power of Sketch lies within its shortcuts. Especially the handling of layers in the layers list can be improved drastically if you memorize some keyboard buttons. </p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Hide a layer</strong>: <kbd>shift</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>H</kbd>. The eye symbol <img src="http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-26-2014-2.png" width="27" height="27" alt="" class="tip-image-inline"> shows that the layer is hidden.</li>
	<li><strong>Lock a layer</strong>: <kbd>shift</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>L</kbd>. The padlock symbol <img src="http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-26-2014-3.png" width="27" height="27" alt="" class="tip-image-inline"> shows that the layer is locked.</li>
	<li><strong>Rename a layer</strong>: <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>R</kbd> followed by <kbd>enter</kbd>.</li>
	<li><strong>Select previous/next layer</strong>: <kbd>tab</kbd> / <kbd>shift</kbd> + <kbd>tab</kbd>. In combination with <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>R</kbd> you can quickly rename multiple layers this way.</li>
	<li><strong>Move a layer to the front/back</strong>: <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>up</kbd> / <kbd>down</kbd></li>
	<li><strong>Make a layer the topmost/bottommost one</strong>: <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>alt</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>up</kbd> / <kbd>down</kbd></li>
</ul><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Show artboard preview</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=23</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: View &gt; Show Artboard Preview</strong></p>

<p>When you are working on a design for your app or website it&rsquo;s often litereally hard to see the big picture. Luckily there is an option in Sketch which lets you preview your current artboard in a separate window &ndash; just like in Photoshop. That is especially useful if you work with multiple displays and are able to place the preview on the other screen this way.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-19-2014.jpg" width="726" height="508" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows a zoomed in design and the Artboard Preview" class="resrc"/><figcaption class="tip-image-text"><a href="http://dribbble.com/shots/1291128-SoundCloud-iOS-Redesign/attachments/179284">Soundcloud Redesign</a> by <a href="http://dribbble.com/GavinAnthony">Gavin Anthony</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>To open this preview window select &ldquo;Show Artboard Preview&rdquo; from the &ldquo;View&rdquo; menu and you get a handy preview pane which you can move around as you wish. If this option is greyed out for you, you may not have created an artboard or your artboard is empty. You also need to have a layer selected.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Simple bitmap editing</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=22</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcuts:</em> <strong>double-click</strong> on an image, then <kbd>del</kbd> or <kbd>backspace</kbd></p>

<p>Although Sketch is based on vectors, there is still a very basic possibility to crop bitmap images. You just need to insert the image, double-click on it and draw a border around the area you want to delete. Then hit <kbd>del</kbd> or <kbd>backspace</kbd> on the keyboard and the selected area is gone.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-12-2014.jpg" width="726" height="450" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows an image with a marque on it" class="resrc"/><figcaption class="tip-image-text">Image by <a href="http://dribbble.com/veeo">Vee-O</a> on <a href="http://666a658c624a3c03a6b2-25cda059d975d2f318c03e90bcf17c40.r92.cf1.rackcdn.com/unsplash_52d5bbef8a613_1.JPG">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>This way you can also copy and paste parts of the image with <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>C</kbd> and <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>V</kbd> like you would normally do. But please be aware that this manipulations can not be reversed at a later time like the boolean operations of layers.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Scale vs. scale</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=21</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Edit &gt; Scale...</strong></p>

<p>In Sketch there are two ways to scale layers. The most obvious possibility is to select the layer and drag the handles to the desired size. However this way the properties like border and shadow size stay at the original size and aren&rsquo;t scaled proportionally. Moreover the resizing can get a bit wonky especially at smaller sizes. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-05-2014-1.png" width="726" height="392" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows a layer and the dialog 'Scale Layers'" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>While you might desire this &ldquo;unproportional&rdquo; behavior sometimes, often you need to scale everything at the same factor. That&rsquo;s when the &ldquo;Scale Layers&rdquo; dialog comes into play. There&rsquo;s even an icon in the Toolbar for that: <img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-feb-05-2014-2.png" width="39" height="39" alt="Icon of the 'Scale Layers' option" class="tip-image-inline">. This dialog lets you resize the layer and all of its properties proportionally, moreover you can exactly define the factor for resizing and get a pixel-perfect result even at smaller sizes.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Link styles</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=20</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>You know these days, when a client asks you to change all the buttons in your mockup from green to red. With a bit of consideration this &ldquo;problem&ldquo; can be quite easily solved in Sketch with its ability to link styles. For this purpose there is a &ldquo;Link&ldquo; button in the top right region of Sketch, which expands an area where all the styles saved so far are shown. To make a new one, click the element which appearance you want to copy and hit the &ldquo;+&ldquo; to add a square that represents the new style.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jan-29-2014-1.jpg" width="726" height="276" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows three layers and the location of the 'Link' button" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>If you want to apply this new style to othere elements, just select them and click on this style tile. After that all elements share the same characteristics and if you change the appearance of one of them, all the other elements get changed too.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jan-29-2014-2.jpg" width="726" height="276" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows three layers that are linked to share the same appearance" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>To delete a style right click on it and select &ldquo;Remove&ldquo;.</p>

<p>In Sketch 3 this functionality is not gone but a bit more streamlined. Instead of tiles you have a dropdown list now with all the shared styles. The exact workflow will be described in a future tip.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Rotate copies</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=19</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Edit &gt; Paths &gt; Rotate Copies (Sketch 3: Layer &gt; Paths &gt; Rotate Copies)</strong></p>

<p>One of the rather hidden yet very useful &ndash; not to say terrific &ndash; features of Sketch is the ability to take a shape and rotate it several times to get different compound shapes or patterns. To use it first select a shape you have created, then go to &ldquo;Edit &gt; Paths &gt; Rotate copies&rdquo; (Sketch 3: Layer &gt; Paths &gt; Rotate Copies). In this dialog you can choose how many additional copies of the layer you want to create.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jan-22-2014-1.jpg" width="726" height="358" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the dialog 'Rotate copies'" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>The best part is, after you have executed this operation, you are presented with a handle which allows you to change the result to create totally different outcomes. Just drag the little circle around and see the magic unfold.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jan-22-2014-2.jpg" width="726" height="596" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the outcome of 'Rotate copies' with 7 rotated traingles" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p><strong>Bonus</strong>: To get quick acces to this feature, you can add it to the Toolbar with a right click. Select &ldquo;Customize toolbar...&rdquo; and drag the icon to the desired location.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Copy CSS attributes</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=18</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Edit &gt; Copy CSS Attributes</strong></p>

<p>Did you ever wish there was an option in Photoshop, which allows you to copy the visual properties of a layer &ndash; like the roundness of the corners, the gradients and the shadows &ndash; to use in CSS? Bad luck for you then. Fortunately Sketch can produce relief.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jan-14-2014.jpg" width="726" height="409" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows a layer with various CSS-ready properties" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Select a layer, preferably with CSS-ready options, go to &ldquo;Edit &gt; Copy CSS Attributes&rdquo; and the magic happens. Paste it into your favourite code editor and all the visual properties are reflected there now. It even works for transformations and gives you the new &ldquo;to&rdquo; syntax for gradients &ndash; but unfortunatley not the dimensions of the element.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Round to nearest pixel edge</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=17</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Edit &gt; Round to Nearest Pixel Edge (Sketch 3: Layer &gt; Round to Nearest Pixel Edge)</strong></p>

<p>When you edit the vector points of a shape it can happen easily that the edges are not pixel-perfect anymore. To get back to sharp edges, you just need to select &ldquo;Round to Nearest Pixel Edge&rdquo; from the &ldquo;Edit&rdquo; menu (in Sketch 3 it can be found in the &ldquo;Layer&rdquo; menu).</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-jan-07-2013.png" width="726" height="528" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the same layer. It  is unoptimized on top and optimized to have sharp edges at the bottom" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>However this option only works if you have two or more layers that have a boolean operation applied (like &ldquo;Union&rdquo;, &ldquo;Substract&rdquo;, &ldquo;Intersect&rdquo; or &ldquo;Difference&rdquo;, as described in the <a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/help/manual/vector-editing/boolean-operations/">Sketch help</a>) and you are in <a href="http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=4">pixel mode</a>. These limitations do not exist anymore in Sketch 3.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Make Grid, part 2</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=16</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Arrange &gt; Make Grid...</strong></p>

<p>Additional to the tip &ldquo;<a href="/?tip=5">Make Grid, part 1</a>&rdquo;, this option also allows to make copies of a single layer with even spacing. First select the layer which you want to copy and distribute.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-24-2013-1.jpg" width="726" height="528" alt="" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>After that choose <strong>Arrange > Make Grid...</strong> from the menu or click on the icon <img src="img/screen-nov-21-2013-4.jpg" width="26" height="26" alt="" class="tip-image-inline"/> in the toolbar (in Sketch 3 it isn&rsquo;t there by default). In the following panel you can select how many columns and rows you need for the layer and the margin in between. The &ldquo;Boxed&rdquo; option works in the same way like described in the former tip. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-24-2013-2.jpg" width="726" height="528" alt="" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>After you click on &ldquo;Arrange&rdquo; the layer gets copied and arranged based on the selected options. </p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Switch between color spaces</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=15</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>A feature in Sketch I&rsquo;ve long overlooked is the ability to switch between the standard color space RGB and HSB (normally called HSL). But it&rsquo;s that easy: just click somewhere between the RGB input fields when in the color selection panel. Then Sketch switches between RGB and HSB.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-21-2013.png" width="726" height="330" alt="Screenshot shows Sketch with the instruction on how to switch color spaces" class="resrc"/></figure><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Vector point options</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=14</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>The different points of a shape &ndash; the vector points &ndash; have different modes, which let you define how a point looks. For example if it&rsquo;s straigt or rounded. Three of the modes have so called control points &ndash; the little handles next to the vector point &ndash; which let you define the curve(s) of the point. The different modes are as follows:</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-17-2013.jpg" width="726" height="504" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the five different vector point options mentioned below" class="resrc"/></figure>

<ol>
	<li><strong>Straight</strong>: There are no control points available, which results in an angular shape.</li>
	<li><strong>Mirrored</strong>: The control points lie on a straght line and have the exact same distance from the vecor point. This results in an even curve.</li>
	<li><strong>Asymmetric</strong>: The control points also lie on the same line, but can be moved independently of each other, which results in different curve radii on each side of the vector point.</li>
	<li><strong>Disconnected</strong>: The control points don&rsquo;t lie on the same line and can be moved individually, which results in two total different curves.</li>
	<li><strong>Rounded</strong>: There are also no control points available, but just like at a rounded rectangle you can define the rounding based on a number. This also results in an even curve.</li>
</ol>

<p>The only difference in Sketch 3 is that these icons are not located in the toolbar anymore but in the Inspector on the right and that they look different and are more self-evident now.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Mathematical operations in input fields</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=13</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Input fields are pretty clever in Sketch. They let you perform mathematical operations like &ldquo;342* 2&rdquo; or &ldquo;209 &minus; 2&rdquo;. The operation is performed on the selected layer(s) as soon as you press <kbd>enter</kbd>. This works for every input field where you can enter numbers, also for text sizes.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-13-2013.jpg?code=234" width="726" height="504" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two input fields with the above mentioned mathematical operations" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p><strong>Bonus</strong>: Numbers in input fields can also be de- and increased with the up and down arrow keys on the keyboard. If you press <kbd>shift</kbd> at the same time, the de- or increments are performed in decadic steps.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Edit vector points</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=12</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>enter</kbd> or <strong>double-click</strong></p>

<p>Since every shape consists of multiple vector points, you can also edit them. After you have selected the shape simply press <kbd>enter</kbd> or double-click on it to edit the points. </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-09-2013.png" width="726" height="354" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two layers, the left shows the 'Edit shape' mode, the right the 'Edit vector points' mode" class="resrc"/><figcaption class="tip-image-text"><a href="http://dribbble.com/shots/1112098-Base-Sketch/">iOS 7 Base Icon by Matthew R. Miller</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>The vector points are indicated by little circles instead of the little squares of the layer handles. To go back to editing the whole shape, press <kbd>esc</kbd> or click anywhere on the canvas.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Quickly create shapes</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=11</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Since the most important feature in every graphic program is actually to create different kinds of shapes, Sketch has a handy shortcut for every important one.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-05-2013.jpg" width="726" height="374" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the shortcuts you use to make different shapes" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>L</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you create a line.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>O</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you create an oval (circle/ellipsis).</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>R</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you create a rectangle (square).</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>U</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you create a rounded rectangle (square).</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>T</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you create text.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>V</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you create a vector shape consisting of multiple vector points.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>P</kbd></p>

<p>Lets you draw a freeform vector, which is smoothed at the end.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcuts:</em> <kbd>shift</kbd> and <kbd>alt</kbd></p>

<p><strong>Bonus</strong>: If you press <kbd>shift</kbd> when creating a rectangle or rounded rectangle, you get a square, for the oval you get a perfect circle, together with the line it contrains the creation to 45 degree steps. When editing a shape it retains its current ratio.</p>

<p>Hitting the <kbd>alt</kbd> key lets you create/manipulate the shapes beginning at the center. Also works together with <kbd>shift</kbd>.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Show color picker</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=10</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>C</kbd></p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-dec-03-2013.png" width="726" height="346" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows how you can use the usage of the color picker" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>This shortcut shows a color picker, which you can use to quickly select a color from your design. You can even move it out of the boundaries of Sketch to measure the color of other GUI elements. You just need to select a layer for this feature to work.</p>

<p><strong>Bonus</strong>: If you are inside the &ldquo;Fill color&rdquo; panel, you can also click on the color picker icon <img src="img/screen-jan-22-2014-3.png" width="25" height="24" alt="Icon of the color picker" class="tip-image-inline"> to pick a color.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Template creation</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=9</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: File &gt; Save as Template&hellip;</strong> and <strong>File > New from Template</strong></p>

<p>When I&rsquo;m working on an iOS app, I like to use this <a href="http://dribbble.com/shots/1117118-iPhone-5-Artboards-sketch
">template</a> by Thierry Teyssier. It displays an iPhone 5 shape around the art board and allows you to easily visualize the design in context at any time. And because the mockup of the device is outside the art board it doesn&rsquo;t get in the way when you design and the focus is kept on the content of the screen.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-29-2013-1.png" width="726" height="380" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two artboards with an iPhone shape around" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Once it&rsquo;s opened you can save it as a template for later: <strong>File > Save as Template&hellip;</strong> Give the template an explicit name like &ldquo;iOS new app&rdquo;. You&rsquo;ll then be able to start from this template whenever you need: <strong>File > New from Template</strong>.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-29-2013-2.png" width="726" height="380" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which is divided into three parts and shows how to set up these shapes" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p><address>This is a guest tip by <a href="http://twitter.com/MaximeCormier" rel="author">Maxime Cormier</a>.</address> He&rsquo;s also the author of the brilliant course &ldquo;<a href="https://www.udemy.com/mobile-app-design-from-scratch/">Mobile App Design from scratch</a>&rdquo;. As a special offer you will get 50 % off with the coupon &ldquo;SKETCHTIPS&rdquo;.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Layer guides</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=8</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>L</kbd></p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-27-2013.jpg" width="726" height="380" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two text layers and two layer guides which border those" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Sketch automatically shows alignment guides when you move layers around or nudge them with the keyboard. However there are still times when you need to set manual guides to line up layers. To do that you first need to show the rulers with <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>R</kbd> (if they are not yet visile) and then double click on the position where you want to set a layer guide. They are then shown as red lines. To toggle the layer guides press <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>L</kbd> repeatedly. This way you switch all alignment guides on and off, not only the ones you have manually set.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Group layers</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=7</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>G</kbd></p>

<p>If you work with layers, you often want to apply options to several of them, for example change the color, resize them altogether &ndash; or simply organize things. To be able to do that that you can make a layer group. Just select all the layers you want to group and press <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>G</kbd>. This way the layers also keep their aspect ratio if you resize them (this does not apply to Sketch 3 anymore). </p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/o=50/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-24-2013-1.jpg" width="726" height="325" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows multiple layers, a part of them is ungrouped, a part is grouped" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Layer groups are depicted with a folder symbol in the layer list and the nested layers below. To ungroup layers again press <kbd>shift</kbd> + <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>G</kbd>.</p>

<p>There are also icons for these two options in the toolbar: <img src="img/screen-nov-24-2013-2.jpg" width="91" height="44" alt="Icons to group/ungroup layers" class="tip-image-inline"/></p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Zooming</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=6</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>+</kbd> and <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>-</kbd></p>

<p>These are the most obvious zooming functions, which let you zoom into and out of the canvas, just like in many other applications. They increase and decrease the zoom level by the double amount each (100 %, 200 %, 400 % ...).

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>0</kbd></p>

<p>Actual size: This option shows the canvas at the actual size, that is 100 %.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>1</kbd></p>

<p>Center canvas: This shortcut zooms the canvas so that all existing elements fill the available screen space. If there is an artboard set, it is centered within the screen.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>2</kbd></p>

<p>Zoom selection: This zooms to the currently selected layer (or layers) so that it covers the whole screen.</p>

<hr/>

<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>cmd</kbd> + <kbd>3</kbd></p>

<p>Center selection: The last one is no zoom function at all, but nevertheless pretty useful. It centers the currently selected layer (or layers) within the canvas, but doesn&rsquo;t alter the actual zoom level.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Make Grid, part 1</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=5</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: Arrange &gt; Make Grid...</strong></p>

<p>This option is not about what you may think. Against its assumed meaning it doesn&rsquo;t make a grid for you to align things but rather distributes the selected layers with a predefined spacing between them. First select all the layers you need to distribute.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-21-2013-1.jpg" width="726" height="465" alt="Screenshot of Sketch with three unaligned layers" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>After that choose <strong>Arrange > Make Grid...</strong> from the Menu. Now you can select how many rows you need and how many columns and the amount of spacing between the elements. In our case we want to make just one row with three columns (since we have three elements) and have a spacing of 10 pixels in between. The last option &ndash; &ldquo;Boxed&rdquo; &ndash; assumes that you want to have a virtual box of the same size around each element, but we turn that off for now.</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-21-2013-2.jpg" width="726" height="484" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the 'Grid tool' panel" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Hit &ldquo;Arrange&rdquo; and the layers are perfectly distributed. There&rsquo;s also a little icon in the toolbar of Sketch <img src="img/screen-nov-21-2013-4.jpg" width="26" height="26" alt="Icon of the 'Make Grid' option" class="tip-image-inline"/> which opens the same dialog (in Sketch 3 this icon isn't shown by default anymore).</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-21-2013-3.jpg" width="726" height="340" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the three layers evenly distributed" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Additionally this option can also be used to <a href="/?tip=16">copy and distribute a single layer</a>.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Show pixels</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=4</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>P</kbd></p>
<!-- <p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: View &gt; Show Pixels</strong></p> -->

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-20-2013.jpg" width="726" height="375" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows the difference between non-pixel and pixel mode" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Although Sketch is a vector-based app, it has a strong relation to pixel dimensions. While you typically want to stay in the &ldquo;vector&rdquo; mode of Sketch when designing, you can switch to the pixel view whenever you want with <kbd>ctrl</kbd> + <kbd>P</kbd>. This way you can inspect how your design will look in the browser or a non-vector based environment at any time. </p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Easily measure distances</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=3</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-shortcut"><em>Shortcut:</em> <kbd>alt</kbd> +  hover</p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-19-2013.jpg" width="726" height="490" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which shows two layer groups whereof the distance is measured with 'Easily measure distances'" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Normally it&rsquo;s pretty tedious to get distances out of a document from a graphical application. Not so in Sketch. Just select the layer from which you want to measure and then hold down the <kbd>alt</kbd> key and hover over another layer where you want to know the distance from.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2, Sketch 3.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Add slices for selection</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=2</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p class="tip-text-menu"><strong>Menu bar: File &gt; Add Slices for Selection</strong></p>

<figure class="tip-image"><img src="http://app.resrc.it/http://www.sketchtips.info/img/screen-nov-18-2013.jpg" width="726" height="270" alt="Screenshot of Sketch which depicts the 'Add slices for selection option'" class="resrc"/></figure>

<p>Sometimes it can be a bit of a hassle if you want to export a whole layer group or multiple layers. To simplify this task you just have to choose the above command and Sketch automatically enters the export panel and encloses the whole selection with the export mark. </p>

<p>In Sketch 3 the slicing process is totally different and not hidden behind a separate dialog anymore but an integral part of the app. I will describe this workflow in a later tip.</p><p>This tip applies to: Sketch 2.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Hello at sketchtips.info</title>
<link>http://www.sketchtips.info/?tip=1</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christian Krammer</dc:creator>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>For the past weeks I&rsquo;ve worked hard to get the site online. Foremost it&rsquo;s meant to be a comprehensive gallery for useful tips about <a href="http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a>. Although it is very easy to learn and master, there are many useful tips which can make the life with the app so much easier. I try to release as much tips as possible per week, but expect about two to three weekly tips.

<p>But sketchtips.info is also kind of a case study for me. In the last time I have read countless articles with so many new techniques and approaches, which I absolutely wanted to employ at a site of mine. For me, the main goals at sketchtips.info were:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Accessibility</strong>: I worked hard so that everything on this site is as accesible as possible with the keyboard and thus for disabled people.</li>
<li><strong>No JavaScript needed</strong>: This site also works when JavaScript is not available or turned off. It may not be as beautiful as the "full-blown" version and there may also be a few minor things missing, but it still is usable. With JS off you can stil read articles, search for them and drop me a line.</li>
<li><strong>Scalable images</strong>: While I planned to use an icon font from the beginning, I realized early that this isn&rsquo;t the best solution. Although such "images" are easy to handle, they aren&rsquo;t supported by Opera Mini, which is especially a problem at mobile phones. Many people use this browser on their phone and since I wanted to make sketchtips.info as accesible as possible, I had to use SVG images for the most important iconography.</li>
<li><strong>Modern vs. old</strong>: This site my not be the fastest, but I tried to optimize it as much as possible. Foremost I used the BBC&rsquo;s <a href="http://responsivenews.co.uk/post/18948466399/cutting-the-mustard">&ldquo;Cutting the mustard&rdquo; technique</a> to split the support between old and modern browsers. That means that old browser get a stripped down experience (see "No JavaScript needed") and modern browser are served the "full-blown" experience. This way I don&rsquo;t have to take care about features, which old browsers don&rsquo;t support, because they don&rsquo;t get it nevertheless. That also means that the "high-end" JavaScript file (and some special CSS) is just served to modern browsers. </li>
<li><strong>Mobile first</strong>: You know the premises: Start small and work your way up. Mobile traffic is exploding and so it&rsquo;s a must to have a site, that works in a broad range of devices. Combined with the above techniques sketchtips.info should work an almost every browser on earth &ndash; at least to a basic degree.</li>
<li><strong>CSS to the max</strong>: I could have done much at sketchtips.info also with jQuery, but I decided to use CSS3 as often as possible &ndash; foremost for animations and transitions. The main reason, why the site still wouldn&rsquo;t work without JS is that I almost exclusively used Ajax to load new content and handle all the processing.</li>
</ul>

<p>These were the main points, which I absolutely wanted to employ at this site. Some areas may still need some work and there may be some devices which don&rsquo;t handle the site well enough, but I&rsquo;m always improving. Please share your thougts about sketchtips.info in the comments.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
